<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><idinfo><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Hiroyuki Matsuda</cntper><cntorg>City of Philadelphia - Fire Department</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist2</cntpos><cntemail>hiroyuki.matsuda@phila.gov</cntemail><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>240 Spring Garden Street</address><city>Philadelphia</city><state>Pennsylvania</state><postal>19123</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr></cntinfo></ptcontac><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>201302</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>publication date</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><citation><citeinfo><origin>City of Philadelphia - Fire Department</origin><pubdate>201302</pubdate><title>Philadelphia Fire Department Facilities</title><onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This layer contains all the facilities which belong to the Fire Department. The data includes Fire Station Number, Engine Number, Ladder Number, Battalion Chief Number, EMS Number, Specifications, and Addresses. SDE Feature Class (point) - Features updated: &lt;22/08/2012&gt; - Attributes updated: &lt;22/08/2012&gt; - Metadata updated: &lt;28/09/2012&gt; - Update Frequency: &lt;as needed&gt; 

Key attribute field names and descriptionsField NameData TypeDescriptionFIRESTA_Long IntegerFire Station IDENGShort IntegerEngine IDLADShort IntegerLadder IDBCShort IntegerBattalion Chief IDMEDTextMedic IDSPCLTextSpecialized ApparatusSPCL2TextSpecialized ApparatusSPCL3TextSpecialized ApparatusLOCATIONTextLocationRADTextRadio BandActiveTextNot Being UsedSPCL, SPCL2, SPCL3 (Specialized Apparatus) AbbreviationsAUAir UnitD1HQDeputy 1 HeadquarterD2HQDeputy 2 HeadquarterEMSHQEMS HeadquarterFABFire Administration BuildingFMUSFire MuseumFOAMSpecialized Engine (Carrying Foam)FTAFire Training AcademyGARTSGraphic Arts DivisionGFGrass FireHAZMTHazmat UnitLTLadder TowerMASmall Marine Unit (Boat)MDMass DecontaminationMUMarine UnitPIPEPipe LinesQUINTSpecialized Engine or Ladder (Quint)RRescueSHOPMaintenance ShopSNORKSpecialized Ladder (Snork)SQRTSpecialized Engine (Squrt)SQUADSpecialized Engine (Squad)WHSEWarehouseRAD (Radio Band) AbbreviationsNRadio Band Works for North Fire SRadio Band Works for South Fire Coordinate systemLambert Conformal Conic, US foot, StatePlane Pennsylvania South, NAD 1983

</abstract><purpose>This layer contains all the facilities which belong to the Fire Department. The data includes Fire Station Number, Engine Number, Ladder Number, Battalion Chief Number, EMS Number, Specifications, and Addresses.</purpose></descript><spdom><bounding><westbc>-75.251284</westbc><eastbc>-74.983868</eastbc><northbc>40.12346</northbc><southbc>39.861393</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt><themekey>society</themekey><themekey>Fire Station</themekey><themekey>Engine</themekey><themekey> Ladder</themekey><themekey>Battalion Chief</themekey><themekey>EMS</themekey><themekey>Fire Administration Building</themekey><themekey>Fire Academy</themekey><themekey>Shop</themekey></theme></keywords></idinfo><distinfo><distliab>The City of Philadelphia makes no warranty or representation, express or implied, with respect to the quality, content, accuracy, completeness, currency, freedom from computer virus, or non-infringement of proprietary rights, of any of the design, information, text, graphics, images, pages, interfaces, links, software, or other materials and items contained in this dataset. All such items and materials are provided on an "as is" basis, and you are fully and solely responsible for your use of them and for any results or consequences of your use. They have been compiled from a variety of sources, including sources beyond the control of the City of Philadelphia and, and are subject to change without notice from the City of Philadelphia. Commercial use is prohibited without the prior written permission of the City of Philadelphia. In no event shall the City of Philadelphia or their agencies, officers, employees, agents, or representatives, be liable for any direct, indirect, special, punitive, incidental, exemplary or consequential damages arising your accessing or using this data, or otherwise arising from the data or from anything contained in or displayed in this data. Nothing contained in or displayed in this data constitutes or is intended to constitute legal advice by the City of Philadelphia or any of their agencies, officers, employees, agents or representatives. These terms and conditions and all disputes arising under these terms and conditions shall be governed, construed and decided in accordance with the laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. The City of Philadelphia reserves the right to revise and change these terms and conditions at anytime and without any notice.</distliab><custom>NOTE: Use this template as a guide to construct your letter requesting City of Philadelphia GIS data. The letter must be on your organization's letterhead, signed by an officer of the corporation/organization, and must include all information requested below. Please pay close attention to items in &lt;bold and underlined&gt; and provide data requested in &lt;brackets&gt;. You will be asked to resubmit your request if all of the requested information is not included. In the event that the requestor is a contractor using the requested data as part of a contract with the City of Philadelphia, request shall reference the City department for which the work is being done. Please direct your request to: City of Philadelphia - MOIS GIS Services Group 1234 Market St., 15th Floor Philadelphia, PA 19107 Attn: Brian Ivey **************************** &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; is requesting a portion of the City of Philadelphia's GIS database &lt;IDENTIFY COVERAGES OR DATA LAYERS REQUESTED&gt; for use in &lt;PROJECT DESCRIPTION&gt; for &lt;DEPARTMENT/AGENCY NAME&gt;. The target area is bounded by &lt;PROJECT BOUNDARIES&gt;. &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; confirms that it will abide by the following conditions for use of this data. &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; will use this database solely in connection with the project described above. For the purpose of any data displayed on a public web site, &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; will remove any attribution from the data that will possibly identify it as being the City of Philadelphia. The database will be deleted from any electronic storage media in possession of XYZ COMPANY at the completion of the project and the CD on which it is delivered will be returned to the Mayor's Office of Information Services. Printed maps or reports of any kind displaying data from this database will be presented only to the participating &lt;NEIGHBORHOODS, CITY AGENCIES, PROJECT COMMITTEES, OTHERWISE APPROPRIATE RECEPIENTS&gt; and only in connection with this project. Display materials generated from this database will not be used on any other project nor for demo or promotional use even if the audience is a City agency unless &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; has obtained a prior written agreement from the Mayor's Office of Information Services. &lt;XYZ Company&gt;will not re-distribute the data in digital format to anyone for any purpose. All persons associated with &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; with access to this database will be informed that it is the property of the City of Philadelphia and advised of the terms under which &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; has agreed to its use. This database was specified to be built according to National Map Accuracy Standards for 1:2400 scale maps, but &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; acknowledges that the City makes no representation about the accuracy of any specific information &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; has requested. &lt;XYZ COMPANY&gt; will assume complete responsibility for any and all occurrences resulting from &lt;XYZ COMPANY'S&gt; use or display of this database. &lt;Signature by Officer of the Corporation/Organization&gt;&lt;/</custom><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>U.S. Grant Ervin</cntper><cntorg>City of Philadelphia, Deputy Mayor's Office of Public Safety</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Public Safety GIS Program Manager</cntpos><cntvoice>215-821-4628</cntvoice><cntfax>215-686-3247</cntfax><cntemail>grant.ervin@phila.gov</cntemail><hours>9am to 5pm</hours></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><spdoinfo><direct>Point</direct><ptvctinf/></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref><metainfo><metd>201302</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo><dataIdInfo><envirDesc>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.0.2414</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="en" country="US"/></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle>GIS_FIRE.Fire_Dept_Facilities</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm></idCitation><descKeys><thesaName uuidref="723f6998-058e-11dc-8314-0800200c9a66"/><keyword>002</keyword></descKeys><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001"/></spatRpType></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="en"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><distInfo><distFormat><formatName>SDE Feature Class</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName>dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="2272"/><idCodeSpace>EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion>7.4.1</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001"/></topLvl><geometObjs><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="004"/><geoObjCnt>0</geoObjCnt></geoObjTyp></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>GIS_FIRE.Fire_Dept_Facilities</enttypl></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FIRESTA_</attrlabl><attrdef>Fire Station ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ENG</attrlabl><attrdef>Engine ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>LAD</attrlabl><attrdef>Ladder ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>BC</attrlabl><attrdef>Battalion Chief ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>MED</attrlabl><attrdef>Medic ID</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>SPCL</attrlabl><attrdef>Specialized Apparatus</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>SPCL2</attrlabl><attrdef>Specialized Apparatus</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>SPCL3</attrlabl><attrdef>Specialized Apparatus</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>LOCATION</attrlabl><attrdef>Location</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>RAD</attrlabl><attrdef>Radio Band</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ACTIVE</attrlabl><attrdef>Not Being Used</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><mdDateSt>20110408</mdDateSt><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA) </cntorg></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>115 Land and Water Building</address><city>University Park</city><state>Pennsylvania</state><postal>16802</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(814) 865 8792</cntvoice><cntemail>pasda@psu.edu </cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab></distinfo></metadata>
